Diego Mauricio Castro Granados

(+57) 300 570 2933 diegomcastrog@gmail.com Linkedin.com/in/diegomcastro/

I am a Software engineer and analyst with 10+ years of experience in enterprise-level applications design and development, using JavaEE, EJB, Kotlin, REST Services, Spring boot, JSF, Docker, PostgreSQL, MongoDB; involved in the whole life cycle of software development for government organizations. I have management-oriented skills and a high capacity for individual and teamwork. I am a disciplined person, leader, critical thinker, and enthusiastic self-learner. I'm willing to acquire new knowledge.

EXPERIENCE

Rappipay - Latam, Senior Backend Java Kotlin Developer— Oct 2021 - Nov 2022

- Led the team of Backend devs and QAs.
- Generate the user interface of the Clarifications and the Help Center area from the backend with the Builder design pattern, and Use of JUnit for testing requirements.
- Design, develop/improve new/existing features for the Bank's microservices, LATAM Operations.

Tech-stack: Kotlin, PostgreSQL, Spring (Boot, Data JPA, Security), Rest, Kafka, Redis, Split, Scrum, Gradle, JPA, Hibernate, JUnit, Mokito, Git, Bitbucket

Unidad de Restitución de Tierras, Senior Developer Analyst— Jul 2015-Nov 2021

- I worked on the development of new modules for victims of forced abandonment and land dispossession in Colombia;
 Claimants were able to make the land claim process 65% faster, reducing the time of the proceedings with the government. Application deployed in several offices in Colombia using JavaEE, EJB, Rest Services, JSF, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and JBoss EAP.
- I proposed an offline mobile solution for data collection in remote areas without internet coverage for victims of forced abandonment and land dispossession in Colombia. It is being developed in Android, Kotlin, Spring boot, and Rest Services.
- Development of modules with the integration of web services of information systems of 12 governmental institutions hosted in a governmental ESB, allowing the exchange of state information, thus reducing consultation time and saving money with the zero paper campaign.
- Change of software architecture of the main system to Rest services, Spring boot, and Angular.

Tech-stack: Spring Framework-based microservices, Hibernate, Maven/Gradle, Scrum

Gobernación de Boyacá - Secretaria de Salud, Developer Analyst - Jan 2014- Ju 12015

In this project I proposed, coordinated, and participated in the development of an application for monitoring and evaluation of municipal health plans (JavaEE, PostgreSQL, Jsf, Hibernate). The solution was able to eliminate the filling of excel forms and provide support to the developed applications.

Universidad de Boyacá – Vicerrectoría de Desarrollo Institucional, Developer Analyst — Oct 2012- Dec 2013

I coordinated and carried out outreach projects with technological character (Digital Marketing) with internal and external scope in the Educational Institution, e-advertising campaigns, and other; development of web pages of the Vice Rectory and other academic sites under CMS Joomla, use of web 2.0 and 3.0 tools.

Caja de compensación Familiar de Boyacá - Comfaboy. Developer Analyst - Sep 2011- Oct 2012

Analysis and software developer for online management of the implementation of thematic content for the training of the different areas, services of the company, and the different Information Systems. Developed with JavaEE, PostgreSQL, Apache.

PROJECTS

TusOfertas.in. —*Apr 2011 – May 2012*

I was Co-founder of the Entrepreneurship Project, which offered advertising services to different commercial establishments in the State of Boyacá. Strategic planning and development of the portal with ASP.Net technology. I was in charge of implementing the web portal oriented to communication and collaboration between companies in the region. It was developed in ASP.Net 4.0, HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: JAVA, HTML, CSS, Kotlin, API REST, Angular, JSF, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Jboss EAP, JSON, Hibernate, JasperReports

Frameworks, and Tools: Spring, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Gitlab, Hibernate

Languages: English B1 - B2; Spanish Native

EDUCATION

IT Systems Management Specialist, Dec 2011

Universidad de Boyacá.

Engineer's degree. Computer Software Engineering, Dec 2009

Universidad de Boyacá.

Red Hat Courses (DO283, DO180, DO101, JB248, JB183) Dec 2019 – Nov 2020 Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC) – Licencia 75956. SCRUMstudy. April 30, 2015

Course Oficial Scrum Master Certified (SMC). SCRUMstudy.